dol.govt.nz 2018-01-27

# Privacy » Employment New Zealand

### No need to disclose personal information

You can use [www.employment.govt.nz](https://www.employment.govt.nz/) without disclosing any personal information.

### Voluntary disclosure of personal information

You may choose to voluntarily provide personal information through this website (eg in ‘ask a question’, or feedback forms). This information may be viewable by site administrators, MBIE staff (as appropriate) and third-party contractors who may administrate or work on the site.

### Electronic alerts and newsletters

When you subscribe to one of our alerts or newsletters, the details you provide may be stored in a secure third-party database (ie Campaign Monitor). Your name and email address will be used to send you future electronic newsletters, and will not be disclosed without your consent. When you unsubscribe to our alert or newsletter, your details will be deleted from the database.

### Collection of personal information

MBIE may ask or require you to provide some personal information when you complete an online form (eg the contact us form). MBIE may require you to register your details with us in order to create or maintain an account or profile (eg Submitting a Record of Settlement to Employment Mediation Services). As part of our online processes there may be other information that is required to be supplied. Failing to provide such information may reduce or make unavailable some services we provide to you. 

We may also ask you to voluntarily provide biographic data. Where you choose to do so, we will use it to understand the customers accessing our services and it may be shared with our team, enabling us to provide better services.

### Holding of information

When you provide personal information, it will be held by MBIE. It may be stored or accessed on behalf of MBIE by authorised third parties (such as third-party contractors) to the extent that is necessary, for example for them to administrate or work on the site. We will store and keep your personal information secure in accordance with the Privacy Act 1993 and agents will be subject to the MBIE's information security and privacy requirements. 

### Disclosure of information

MBIE will generally not share personal information that is provided or collected through this website, unless it is necessary to do so for the purpose for which you gave us the information (eg to investigate a complaint, or to manage or schedule a mediation) or where you consent. MBIE will not otherwise disclose personal information provided or collected through this website unless required or otherwise permitted by law.

### Use of personal information

MBIE will generally only use personal information provided to us through this website for the purpose you provided it (eg to administer, evaluate and improve the site, to improve our services, or to action or respond to the information provided). We may also use personal information provided to us through this website for other reasons permitted under the Privacy Act 1993 (eg with your consent, for a directly related purpose, or where the law permits or requires it).
